This task is about the mathematical and graphical
representation of Petri Nets. More specifically,
in this task, it's our task to represent this
given Petri Net in the mathematical notation
as its graphical representation.
And we have been given the five tuple of the
Petri Net which includes places and transitions.
In this case, there are four places labeled
s1 to s4 and five transitions labeled t1 to
t5.
There are the definitions for the transitions
or more specific for the edges, which lead
from places to transitions, and from transitions
to places.
There are markings defined as well.
We start by placing these places and these
transitions and then we can think about how
to represent the Petri Net.
I've already got these transitions and these
places, and now, we require to add edges between
the transitions and places between.
Before we do that, we can think also about
how we want to lay out our graph.
And therefore, before we start on this, we
can check where are transitions or where are
edges going from and to?
And when we look at these definitions here,
we find the information that is required for
our Petri Net here.
And we see that in this case, there is an
edge between
the transition t1 on place s1, and we see
that this transition is going to s2.
We can think of t1 being in the middle of
s1 and s2 somewhere.
The next definition is for t2 already, so
we can check and t2 is having s2 and
s3 as neighboring edges or we could place
t2 somewhere in between those two and then
we have a t3 and this one is between s3 and
s1.
We could place t3 somewhere between them,
let's say here.
We have t4 which is between s1 and s4.
And as there is t2 in the middle at the moment,
maybe we want to place s4 at a different place.
So, we have for t4, we have s1 and s4.
So maybe place this somewhere
here maybe.
And now we require t4 to be between s1 and
s4 and we have t5 left and this one is connected
to s3 and s4.
That is why we should place t5 probably somewhere
here.
And now we have just a basic layout so that
we maybe do not have as much overlappings
or do not expect very many overlappings.
So now we can start drawing edges between
those.
And we start by placing s1 here for transition
one, so we go for all the transitions.
And this is an ingoing edge to transition
one.
That is why we have an arrow between s1 and
t1 going from s1 to t1.
And then there's the outgoing edge from t1
to s2.
And so we continue from s2 to t2, from t2
to s3, from s3 to t3, from t3 to s1.
And we scroll down, there we have s1 to t4,
t4 to s4, s3 to t5 and s4 to t5.
And maybe we move this layer here off s4,
so that it's more visible we move it inside, to get
a more dense graph, it doesn't matter really.
Just that we can see the labels all because
it was hidden behind an arrow at the moment.
Now it looks a bit better.
And now we have all the edges, but I did not
calculate the numbers yet.
And for once, we do not have to write numbers
at the edges.
But if the transition contains more than one,
then we have to add a number.
And we do not require those numbers because
by default, the weight of the edge is one.
And if there is no edge, for instance between
s1 and t2 there is no edge, this means that
the weight of this connection is zero.
That is why we have the weight of one if there
is an arrow.
But for our representation here, we have
sometimes two or so.
And this is for instance from the outgoing
edge of t3 to s1.
And in this case, we should add the weight
of two to this edge here.
And then there is also a weight of two for
the ingoing edge to t5 from s4.
So this is this edge here and we should add
weight of two here as well.
So, now we considered all the weights, but
we are still not done with the graph as we
require our initial marking.
And we get this defined here that for s1 and
for s4, there should be one token and for
s2 and s3, there should be zero tokens.
There are no tokens at all at the moment,
so we just require to add tokens to s1 and
to s4.
So, we add those tokens here.
When we’ve finally done this, then we are
ready with our Petri Net and this should be
the Petri Net that we want to have for this
task.
It can look different of course, if you have
a different layout, but that's how we get
the Petri Net in the graphical representation.